# Curriculum Vitae

## Pawel Sawicz

#### Personal Informations

Telephone +44 079 403 287 80
E-MAIL pawel@sawicz.eu
Blog pawel.sawicz.eu

GITHUB github.com/pawelsawicz

## Profile

Engineering Lead specialising in distributed systems and building products. Crazy about learning new things, but balanced when taking a risk. In spare time trying to understand type theory and constructive logic. Heavily involved in .NET community, co-organizer virtual conference, moreover attendee and speaker of several conferences around Europe.

## Work Experience

Period January 2021 — Present

Employer Checkout.com London, United Kingdom

Job Title Engineering Lead - Arundel Squad

Leading a squad of 5 developers. Being responsible for mentoring, managing and paving a technical vision for reconciliation product. Successfully delivered reconciliation product that decreased manual effort of reconciling transactions from 6 working hours to 15 minutes with a cover of 65 % of Checkout transaction volume.

Helping Checkout to scale world wide with right reconciliation tools that will cover all world transactions. Technologies:

- DevOps (AWS, Terraform, Docker)
- Messaging (SQS, SNS, Kinesis),
- Coding (.NET/C#)
- Monitoring/Logging (Prometheus, DataDog, Grafana)

PERIOD **EMPLOYER IOB TITLE** 

September 2019 — January 2021

Checkout.com

London, United Kingdom

Senior Software Engineer - FORT team

Building reconciliation products for the finance department within Checkout. Working with the team on architecture design, mentoring peers, heavily involved in the recruitment process. Being involved in shaping team structure. Top projects:

- Transaction alerting product. Product that runs buissnes checks on all transactions (i.e Has a transaction been successfully sent to clearing within T+1)
- Debtor rolling position. Reporting product showing how much money Checkout owns to card schemes (Visa/Mastercard)

#### Technologies:

- DevOps (AWS, Terraform, Docker)
- Messaging (SQS, SNS, Kinesis),
- Coding (.NET/C#)
- Monitoring/Logging (Prometheus, DataDog, Grafana)

PERIOD **EMPLOYER** JOB TITLE

March 2016 — August 2019

Zopa

London, United Kingdom

## Software Engineer

Worked on the core part of Zopa business. Being exposed to all parts of Zopa business (Bank, Borrowing, Lending). Being involved and leading architectural decisions across the whole business.

Top project:

- Rolling out new loan algorithm impacting 95% of existing loan book (4.5bln pounds)
- Zopa Auto product, greenfield project that is adopted by the Car industry, revolutionising car loan industry (Adopted by all major players) est. market cap 10bln pounds.
- Enabled Zopa Bank launch by working on key projects.
- Involved in the recruitment process, being involved in around 200 interviews at various stages (code review, phone interview, face to face).
- Responsible for extracting microservices out of the monolith.

Technologies: CQRS, EventSourcing, DDD, Jenkins, Packer, Splunk

Period July 2014 — February 2016

EMPLOYER JustGiving London, United Kingdom

JOB TITLE API Developer / Evangelist

Being involved in forming API team and shaping its form. I am very proud to have founded and grown the community arund the JG public api. I helped out and hosted events and international hackathons. To technical side of role belonged: creating architecture of API, maintaining and monitoring health of API, supporting customers in case of technical problems. Many contribution to core JustGiving codebase, re-factoring old parts of API, writing TDD. Overview of technologies: NancyFx, WebApi, Owin, ASP. MVC, Microservices, CQRS. Heavily worked in cloud enviroment, Amazon Web Services, used tools like: Raygun, Kibana, Chef, Vagrant, GO CD

Period July 2013 — June 2014

EMPLOYER Neurosys Wroclaw, Poland

JOB TITLE Junior .NET Developer

Involved in maintaince and development of new features. Writing unit tests to cover fragile parts of the code. Worked as fronted and backend developer. Responsible for implementing RWD in two projects, worked with knockout and

ASP.NET MVC/Web API

Period June 2011 — September 2011, August 2012 — September

2012

EMPLOYER Chroma.pl Zary, Poland

JOB TITLE Junior .NET Developer

Responsible for one major feature addon. Created unit test to cover code. Worked with 'ling to excel' library. Prepared SQL queries. Created library that checks the e-mail, by

RCPT protocol.

## **EDUCATION**

Period October 2011 — February 2015

Degree Bachelor of Science

UNIVERSITY Wroclaw University of Technology
FIELD Electronic & Telecommunication

Period October 2018 — January 2022

DEGREE Master of Science
University University of Oxford

FIELD Computer Software Engineering

## ACTIVITIES

- Active memeber of .NET Group (PWr Wroclaw)
- Imagine Cup participant (2012, 2013 editions)
- 2012 edition Tourist Guide

Web application which provide information about travelling and sightseeing.

- 2013 edition - BusCatcher

Windows Phone 7 application which use external API to gather information about current position of public transport vehicles

- dotNetConfPL co-organizer

First polish virtual conference about .net - 200 attendees

## LANGUAGES

ENGLISH Fluent
Polish Native